Katherine Leonard

Phone: 971-801-4768 Website: katieleonard.ca
Email: keighty.leonard@gmail.com GitHub: github.com/keighty

LinkedIn: ca.linkedin.com/in/katieleonard

Summary

• Motivated software developer with experience in JavaScript, Java, Ruby

- Passionate about learning and mentoring
- Creative problem solver

• Strong written and verbal communication skills

Skills

Software Development: JavaScript (React, Angular, D3, Node), Java, Ruby, Rails

Operating Systems: Linux (Ubuntu), OSX

Social: Creative, flexible, resourceful problem solver, focused,

organized, articulate

Professional Experience

New Relic, Portland, OR

Nov 2013 - Present

Browser UI Team

- Continued development work on backend Java services and the JSAgent
- Built frontend user interfaces (React)

Browser Agent Team

- Contributed to improved instrumentation for single page applications (JavaScript)
- Developed endpoints for processing high throughput data (Java)

RPM Foundations Team

- Project coordinator and developer on Rails upgrade of the main product code base (3.0 to 3.2)
- On-call responsibility

APM Transactions Team

- Developed a D3 tree visualization for cross-application transaction tracking
- Worked in Angular building a thread profiler UI for Java applications

Biospective Inc., Montreal, Quebec Canada

Nov 2007 - May 2013

Research Associate

- Wrote a shell tool for extracting and analysing physiological data
- Managed Oracle database for document management system
- Wrote SQL tools and HTML forms for process reporting
- Developed and implemented standard operating procedures and laboratory protocols
- Developed, implemented, and validated project specific applications to track clinical trial data in a CFR/Part 11 regulatory compliant manner

Education

Portland Code School | Portland, OR

2013

McGill University | Montreal, Quebec

2009 - 2011

Certificate in Software Development -- Dean's Honor List

Simon Fraser University | Vancouver, British Columbia

1998 - 2002

BSc. Science, English Minor, and Certificate Liberal Arts

Hobbies and Affiliations

American Contract Bridge League | Life Master Royal Montreal Curling Club | Member